Anna Hyatt Huntington Papers
Anna Hyatt Huntington Papers
- Photographs
  - Artwork by AHH
    - Horses on wave, oversize, "White horses of the sea" (Oversize 9)
    - Horses, various (Box 90)
    - Horsetamer, "Youth"or "Youth conquering the wild" (Box 90)
    - Horsetamer, oversize, "Youth"or "Youth conquering the wild" (Oversize 12)
    - Israel Putnam (Box 90)
    - Israel Putnam, oversize (Oversize 12)
    - Jaguar, crawling off rock (Box 90)
    - Jaguar, head (Box 90)
    - Jaguar, letter opener (Box 90)
    - Jaguar, on rock (Box 90)
    - Jaguars, group (Box 91)
    - Jaguars, various (Box 91)
    - Jaguars, oversize (Oversize 10)
    - Joan of Arc, equestrian statue (Box 91)
    - Joan of Arc, equestrian statue, oversize (Oversize 10)
    - Joan of Arc, human statue at Saint John the Divine (Box 91)
    - Joan of Arc, medal (Box 91)
    - Jose Marti (Box 91)
    - Jose Marti, oversize (Oversize 12)
    - Knight on horseback (Box 91)
    - Lady Godiva (Box 91)
    - Lamb, lying down (Box 91)
    - Lion, seated (Box 91)
    - Lion, seated with orb (Box 91)
    - Lion and lioness (Box 91)
    - Lion on rock (Box 91)
    - Lion cubs playing (Box 91)
    - Lioness, seated (Box 91)
    - Lions, various (Box 91)
    - Lions, oversize (Oversize 12)
    - Man with sword, seated (1) (Box 91)
    - Man with sword, seated (2) (Box 91)
    - Man with sword, seated (3) (Box 91)
    - Man with sword, seated (4) (Box 91)
    - Marabou with fish, "Whose fish?" (Box 91)
    - Medals, various (Box 91)
    - Memorial to fishermen lost at sea (Box 91)
    - Merman (?) with dragon / sea serpent (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Huey again reaching for food" (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Huey asleep at last" (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Huey cleaning his coat" (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Huey, pouch full" (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Huey reaching for food" (Box 91)
    - Monkey, "Study of Huey" (Box 91)
    - Monkey and bird (Box 91)
    - Monkey, head (Box 91)
    - Monkey on all fours (Box 91)
    - Monkey on branch (Box 91)
    - Monkey scratching (Box 91)
    - Monkeys grooming each other (Box 91)
    - Monkeys, pair (Box 91)
    - Monkeys, shrieking (ring-tailed lemurs?), "Hymn of hate" (Box 91)
    - Monkeys sleeping, statue (Box 91)
    - Monkeys sleeping, wall plaque (Box 91)
    - Monkeys, various (Box 91)
    - Monks, kneeling, various (Box 92)
    - Mother and child (Box 92)
    - Mountain sheep (Box 92)
    - Nurse, Danbury Hospital (Box 92)
    - Old man and young woman, "Youth and old age," "Wartime Refugee" (Box 92)
    - Old woman, seated, "Grandma Beebe, about 1953" (Box 92)
    - Owl with fish (Box 92)
    - Panels, animal heads (Box 92)
    - Panels, human heads (Box 92)
    - Panther, Myrtle Beach, SC, Air Force Base (Box 92)
    - Peacocks fighting (Box 92)
    - Peacocks fighting, oversize (Oversize 9)
    - Pigs, group (Box 92)
    - Rhinoceros bookends (Box 92)
    - Rhinoceros charging (Box 92)
    - Russian wolfhound (Box 92)
    - St. Francis, two different ones (Box 92)
    - Seals (Box 92)
    - Swan (Box 92)
    - Swan and young (Box 92)
    - Swan, grooming breast (Box 92)
    - Swan, grooming wing (Box 92)
    - Swan, head (Box 92)
    - Swans, pair (Box 92)
    - Sybil Ludington (Box 92)
    - Sybil Ludington, oversize (Oversize 12)
    - Theodore Roosevelt, medal (Box 92)
    - Tiger and bird (Box 92)
    - Tiger jumping for bird (Box 92)
    - Tigers on rock (Box 92)
    - Tigers sleeping (Box 92)
    - Tigers, various (Box 92)
    - Torchbearer, University of South Carolina (Box 92)
    - Torchbearers, 2 folders (Box 92)
    - Torchbearers, oversize (Oversize 13)
    - Turtle (Box 93)
    - Victorious Resolute crew, medal (Box 93)
    - The Visionaries, Archer Milton Huntington memorial (Box 93)
    - Vultures (Box 93)
    - Vultures, oversize (Oversize 13)
    - William Dean Howells, medal (Box 93)
    - Wild boar (Box 93)
    - Wild boar group (Box 93)
    - Wild boar, oversize (Oversize 13)
    - Wolves, howling (Box 93)
    - Woman in the wind, 2 different ones (Box 93)
    - Woman on mule, 1959; "Queen Isabella on muleback" (Box 93)
    - Zebra with foal (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous animals (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous human figures (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous human figures, oversize, bust of woman (Oversize 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 93)
    - Scrapbooks, 5 volumes (Box 123)
    - Scrapbooks, 3 volumes (Box 124)
    - Scrapbook, 1 volume (Oversize 6)
  - Artwork by others
    - Dallin, Cyrus, "The Scout" (Box 93)
    - Eberle, Abastenia St. Leger, bust of AHH (Box 93)
    - Fraser, James Earle, "End of the Trail" (Box 93)
    - Graner, Luis, portraits, Mrs. Craig Biddle and Mrs. Leonard M. Thomas (Box 93)
    - Keck, Charles, "Andrew Jackson" (Box 93)
    - Lane, Katherine, greyhound stretching (Box 93)
    - Lockman, DeWitt M., portrait of officer, horse (Oversize 1)
    - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt, one photo of a sculpture of a boy and a dog, is annotated on the back as "Anna V. Hyatt and Harriet Randolph Hyatt, only piece done together" (Box 93)
    - Proctor, Phimister, "Pioneer Mother" (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Exhibits
    - Carnegie Institue, Pittsburgh, PA, 1937, June 3-20 (Box 94)
    - Palace of the Legion of Honor, San Francisco, CA, 1937, summer (Box 94)
    - Los Angeles Museum of History, Science and Art, Los Angeles, CA, 1937, August (Box 94)
    - Los Angeles Museum of History, Science and Art, Los Angeles, CA, 1937, August (Oversize 1)
    - Fine Arts Gallery, San Diego, CA, 1937, September (Box 94)
    - Isaac Delgado Museum, New Orleans, LA, 1937, October (Box 94)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, Memphis, TN, 1937, November (Box 94)
    - City Art Museum, St. Louis, MO, 1937, "late" (Box 94)
    - Toledo Museum of Art, Toledo, OH, 1938, February (Box 94)
    - Corcoran Gallery, Washington, DC, 1938, March (Box 94)
    - Gallery of Fine Arts, Yale University, 1938, April 3-24 (Box 94)
    - Berkshire Museum, Pittsfield, MA, 1938, May (Box 94)
    - Currier Gallery of Art, Manchester, NH, 1938, August (Box 94)
    - Mint Museum of Art, Charlotte, NC, 1938, December (Box 94)
    - Wadsworth Athenaeum, Hartford, CT, 1938 (Box 94)
    - Carolina Art Association, Gibbes Memorial Art Gallery, Charleston, SC, 1939, January (Box 94)
    - Telfair Academy, Savannah, GA, 1939, February (Box 94)
    - William and Mary College, Williamsburg, VA, 1939, March (Box 94)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Philadelphia, PA, 1939, April 5-26 (Box 94)
    - Newark Museum, Newark, NJ, 1939, May (Box 94)
    - Florence Museum, Florence, SC, 1940, February (Box 94)
    - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, 1943, November (Box 94)
    - Palace of the Legion of Honor, San Francisco, CA, 1944 (Box 94)
    - Museum of Modern Art, Madrid, Spain, 1955? (Box 94)
    - YWCA, Athens, Greece, 1955? (Box 94)
    - Norfolk Museum, Norfolk, VA, 1961, summer (Box 94)
    - Mariners Museum, Newport News, VA, 1962, September 3 (Box 94)
    - Museum of SUNY Albany, Albany, NY, 1963, December (Box 94)
    - Manor Club, Pelham, NY, 1965, February (Box 94)
    - Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY (?), after 1960 (Box 94)
    - Addison Gallery, Andover, MA, Undated (Box 94)
    - Joslyn Memorial, Omaha, NE, Undated (Box 94)
    - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, Springfield, MA, Undated (Box 94)
    - University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA, Undated (Box 94)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, New York, NY, Undated (Box 94)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Box 94)
    - Unidentified, oversize, Undated (Oversize 1)
  - Family
    See also Memorabilia: Scrapbooks: Family photos (labeled) (Oversize 4) for additional family photographs.
    - Beebe, Lidia Ann, AHH's grandmother (Box 95)
    - Hatzfeldt, Clara Elizabeth, Archer's sister (Box 95)
    - Hodgdon, Dana and Clara Hyatt, AHH's niece and her husband (Box 95)
    - Huntington, Anna Hyatt, 4 folders (Box 95)
    - Huntington, Anna Hyatt (oversize) (Oversize 14)
    - Huntington, Anna Hyatt (oversize) (Oversize 15)
    - Huntington, Archer (Box 95)
    - Huntington, Archer, 2 folders (Box 96)
    - Huntington, Archer, oversize (Oversize 1)
    - Huntington, Collis P., Archer's father (Box 96)
    - Huntington, Harriet, Archer's aunt? (Box 96)
    - Huntington, Henry E. II (Box 96)
    - Huntington, Henry E. II (oversize) (Oversize 1)
    - Hyatt, Alpheus, AHH's father (Box 96)
    - Hyatt, Alpheus, oversize (Oversize 1)
    - Hyatt, Audella Beebe, AHH's mother; 2 folders (Box 96)
    - Hyatt, Audella Beebe, oversize, painting from daguerreotype of Audella, age 9 (Oversize 1)
    - Hyatt, Harriet Randolph King, AHH's grandmother (Box 96)
    - Hyatt, Harriet Randolph King (oversize) (Oversize 1)
    - Mayor, A. Hyatt and Virginia, AHH's nephew (Box 96)
    - Mayor, Brantz and Evelyn, AHH's nephew (Box 97)
    - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt, AHH's sister (Box 97)
    - Yarrington family, Archer's grandparents (Box 97)
    - Miscellaneous family (Box 97)
    - Unidentified friends or family, 3 folders (Box 97)
    - Unidentified friends or family (oversize) (Oversize 1)
  - Family property
    - Atalaya, Huntington home at Brookgreen, designed by Archer (Box 97)
    - Brookgreen Gardens (Box 98)
    - C. P. Huntington house, 57th St, New York (oversize) (Oversize 1)
    - Huntington tomb (Box 98)
    - New York house, E. 89th St. (Box 98)
    - New York house, E. 89th St. (oversize) (Oversize 1)
    - "Pleasaunce" (Box 98)
    - Rocas, house in Haverstraw, New York (Box 98)
    - Stanerigg, in Redding, Connecticut (Box 98)
    - Stanerigg [?] (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 98)
  - People
    - Bohnert, Herbert, American artist (1888-1967) (Oversize 1)
    - Canas, Jose Simeon, Latin American scholar and abolitionist (1767-1838) (Oversize 1)
    - Carroll, Seymour, prominent African-American, Columbia, SC (Box 99)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Oversize 1)
    - Flagg, — (Dr.), neighbor at Brookgreen (Box 99)
    - Franco, Francisco, dictator of Spain (1892-1975) (Oversize 1)
    - Guardabassi, [Mariano?], possibly the Italian archaeologist (Box 99)
    - Howells, William Dean, American author and critic (1837-1940) (Box 99)
    - Pardee, E.H., possibly Enoch H. Pardee, California eye doctor and politician (Box 99)
    - Peary, Robert E., American explorer (1856-1920) (Box 99)
    - Rickover, Hyman, American admiral (1900-1986) (Box 99)
    - Queen Victoria, English monarch (1819-1901) (Box 99)
    - Volpe, John Anthony, governor of Massachusetts; photo is of his three children (Box 99)
    - Unidentified, 1 item (Oversize 1)
  - Places
    - Africa (Box 99)
    - France (Box 99)
    - Monaco (Box 99)
    - Pinenut? (Box 99)
    - South America (Box 99)
    - Spain (Box 99)
    - Spain, University of Madrid (Box 99)
    - Switzerland, Leysin (Box 99)
    - United Kingdom (Box 99)
    - United States, Nashville (Box 99)
    - United States, New Orleans (Box 99)
    - United States, New York City (Box 99)
    - United States, Rollins College, Winter Park, FL (Box 99)
    - United States, Texas (Box 99)
    - United States, Tucson (Box 99)
    - Unidentified, United States? (Box 100)
    - Unidentified, non-U.S. (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Films
      - [according to old finding aid, either "Havana Jan 1929" or "setting J's statue on Roosevelt Memorial, Roosevelt equestrian, 1934, 1940"], huntington_001; Film: 16mm, silent
      - [according to old finding aid, either "Havana Jan 1929" or "setting J's statue on Roosevelt Memorial, Roosevelt equestrian, 1934, 1940"], huntington_002; Film: 16mm, silent
      - Torch Bearer, huntington_003; Film: 16mm, silent
    - Negatives, includes 2 glass plate negatives; 5 folders (Box 100)
    - Photo plates, plates for printing photographs; includes deerhounds as well as sculpture and other pictures (Box 101)
    - Photo plates, plates for printing photographs; includes deerhounds as well as sculpture and other pictures (Box 102)
    - Slides, Atalaya/Brookgreen, Stanerigg, Statue Madrid, Archer/Rocas, Rocas, unlabelled, assorted small boxes and loose slides; 6 slide boxes (Oversize 16)
- Printed material
  - Articles
    - About AHH
      - 1933-1934, 1936-1943, 1946-1950, 1953-1968, 1970, undated, 6 folders (Box 103)
      - Oversize, 1934; 1950 (Box 111)
    - About family (Box 104)
    - About others, 1928-1941; 1947-1966,; undated; 2 folders (Box 104)
  - Books
    - About AHH
      - Royere, Jean / Le Musicisme Sculptural: Madame Archer Milton Huntington, 1933 (Box 104)
      - Sapieha, Virgilia / Eminent Women Recipients of the National Achievement Award, 1948 (Box 104)
      - Schaub-Koch, Emile / Anna Hyatt Huntington, Sculpteur de la vie, 1964; inscribed to AHH "from your devoted admirer"; 3 copies (Box 104)
      - Schaub-Koch, Emile / Physiologie esthetique de l'oeuvre animaliere d'Anna Hyatt Huntington, 1962; 2 copies (Box 104)
      - Schaub-Koch, Emile / Le role de la lumiere dans la scultpure d'Anna Hyatt Huntington, 1965 (Box 104)
    - By Archer Milton Huntington
      - Quatre Poemes, 1933 (Box 104)
    - By others
      - Inscribed to AHH, 8 volumes (Box 105)
      - Miscellaneous, includes children's books, a book on Huntington, West Virginia, and a copy of The chivalry of Scotland in the days of King Robert Bruce (1848); 9 volumes (Box 105)
  - Clippings
    - About AHH
      - 1902-1951, 7 folders (Box 106)
      - 1952-1965, 7 folders (Box 107)
      - 1966-1972, 1975, undated, 2 folders (Box 108)
      - (oversize), 1934; 1950; includes two large proof sheets (from newspaper?), rolled (Box 111)
    - About family (Box 108)
    - About others
      - 1919, 1921, 1923, 1925-1934, 1936-1942, 1945-1946, 1948-1968, 6 folders (Box 108)
      - Undated (Box 109)
  - Exhibit catalogs and brochures
    - of AHH's work, 1915; 1927,; 1934,; 1936-1940,; 1942-1944,; 1946,; 1948-1966,; 1968,; 1973,; undated; 7 folders (Box 109)
    - of others' work (Box 110)
  - Press releases
    - By/about AHH (Box 110)
  - Miscellany, 1903; 1930s-1970s; fliers, advertisements, programs, pamphlets, newsletters, etc etc etc; 6 folders (Box 110)
  - Miscellany, mostly magazines (English, French, Spanish) (Box 111)
- Reference files
  - Clippings and photos
    - Aardvarks, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Anteaters, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Armadillo and pangolin, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Bears, see also polar bears; 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Beavers, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Birds, 7 folders (Box 112)
    - Buffalo (African and American), 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Camels, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Capybara (Box 112)
    - Cats, domestic, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Cats, wild, jaguars, cheetahs, mountain lions, bobcats, etc. See also Lions, Tigers; 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Cattle and oxen (Box 112)
    - Cattle and oxen, 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Crocodiles and alligators, 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Deer and antelope, 6 folders (Box 113)
    - Dogs, domestic, includes wolfhounds and deerhounds; one folder is placed lengthwise along the side of the box; 6 folders (Box 113)
    - Donkeys, burros, mules (Box 113)
    - Elephants, 4 folders (Box 113)
    - Fish and other sea creatures, includes coral, shellfish, etc.; 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Foxes, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Frogs and toads (Box 114)
    - Giraffes, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Goats, includes mountain goats, ibexes, etc; 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Hippos, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Horses, 11 folders (Box 114)
    - Hyenas, 2 folders (Box 115)
    - Insects and spiders (Box 115)
    - Kangaroos and wallabies, 2 folders (Box 115)
    - Lions, 3 folders (Box 115)
    - Lizards, 2 folders (Box 115)
    - Llama and alpaca, 2 folders (Box 115)
    - Man, 10 folders (Box 115)
    - Man, 4 folders (Box 116)
    - Moles (Box 116)
    - Monkeys, chimps and apes, includes gorillas; 3 folders (Box 116)
    - Moose, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Opossum, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Otters, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Penguins (Box 116)
    - Pigs, wild and domestic, includes warthogs, wild board, javelina; 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Polar bears, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Porcupines, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Rabbits, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Raccoons (Box 116)
    - Rhinoceros, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Seals and sea lions, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Sheep, includes mountain sheep; 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Sloth (Box 116)
    - Snakes, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Squirrels, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Tapir, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Tigers, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Turtles and tortoises, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Weasels, stoats, ferrets, mink, etc (Box 117)
    - Wildebeest (gnus), 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Wolves and coyotes, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Woodchucks (Box 117)
    - Zebras, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Miscellaneous, animals; 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Miscellaneous, buildings, landscapes, ornamentation, plants, etc (Box 117)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Books, includes multi-volume "Wonders of Animal Life" EXTREMELY HEAVY (Box 118)
    - Clippings (oversize), animals, people; from magazines, newspapers, etc (Oversize 17)
    - Magazines, animals; people; nudes; a few oversize photos of horses (Box 119)
    - Scrapbooks, photos, clippings; mostly animals; one is labelled "Animal Life in the Zoo of Schönbrunn 43 plates"; 6 volumes (Box 120)
- Writings (of others)
  - American Conservative Union / "A Program for American Survival 1973-1978", typescript (Box 121)
  - Bulkeley, Benjamine / "Dearest of my distant kin", typescript poem (Box 121)
  - Cook, Doris / Woman sculptor Anna Hyatt Huntington", See Correspondence-subject files: Cook, Doris
  - Gumilev, Nikolai / "The Giraffe", typescript poem, translated by Y. Hornstein (Box 121)
  - Hathaway, Joy, original illustrations and manuscript (Box 121)
  - Huntington, Archer Milton, typescript and handwritten poems; see also Memorabilia: Miscellaneous: Huntington, Archer Milton (Box MemOS) (Box 121)
  - Huntington, Archer Milton, poem, "Genius," directed "to the Academy of Arts and Letters" (Oversize 3)
  - Malley, Charles, typescripts of "The Example Setters" and "The Imitators"; proof copy of an article (Box 121)
  - Martin, Kay, typescript poems; Kay Martin was Nora Moore-Anderson's mother (Box 121)
  - Meeker, Jay Hathaway, handwritten poem (Box 121)
  - Norton, Frederick H. / "Art and Science in Sculpture", proof copy (Box 121)
  - O'Connor, Jay / "Surpassing Venus", cover, 1 page (Box 121)
  - Royere, Jean, mimeographed booklets, in French (Box 121)
  - Schaub-Koch, Emile, 2 folders (Box 121)
    Typescripts of:
    Preface for L'oeuvre d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
    L'Ame; De l'abstraction dans la statuaire d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
    De la beaute et de l'universalite dans l'oeuvre d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
    L'oeuvre d'Anna Hyatt Huntington et le probleme d'un nouvel humanisme
    Hindu art and the art of Anna Hyatt Huntington
    Anna Hyatt Huntington and the Hindu people
    Physiologie esthetique de l'oeuvre d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
    Deux statues inachevees d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
    De Pisanello a Pompon en passant par Barye, Sandoz, et d'Anna Hyatt Huntington
  - Schaub-Koch, Emile, L'oeuvre d'Anna Hyatt Huntington; typescript and handwritten sketch of cover; 1 folder + 2 volumes (Box 122)
  - Varney, Ruth, handwritten piece, "Immortality," bound with ribbon (Box 122)
  - Vega, Rafael, original music manuscript; 1 page (Box 122)
  - Wilmot, Dorothy E. / "In Sculptor's Studio", typescript poem (Box 122)
  - No author / "A research of the frequency of words in spoken Spanish", typescript research proposal (Box 122)
  - No author / "Traveling costume and saddle of Isabel the Catholic", typescript, includes captioned photographs (Box 122)
  - Unidentified miscellany (Box 122)